30 Willow park Drive Brampton, ON, L6R2N2 Contact No: 647-534-9911 Email: arshdeepdhanjal097@gmail.com

Profile:

Energetic, hard-working student, interest in obtaining a position enabling me to utilize my teamwork abilities and technical skills that offers growth and advancement opportunities.

- Current GPA: 3.89
- Worked at West Corporation as co-op student
- Currently pursuing CCNA Routing & Switching
- Volunteer as Peer Tutor

Skills and Abilities:

Programming Skills:

- Excellence in Java, C, C++, C#, .NET Framework
- Proficient with web dev technologies(HTML5, CSS3, PHP, JS, AJAX, ASP, XML, JSON, ¡Query)
- Strong command in different scripting languages (Python, Shell scripting, VB Scripts)
- Perfection in J2EE web apps(Servlets, JSPs, JSTL, JDBC/ODBC, MVC, Glassfish, Tomcat)

Networking Skills:

- Hands on experience with Cisco Routers (2800, 2900, 3800 series) and Switches (2960,3560 series)
- Practical knowledge of networking concepts (OSI, TCP/IP, IP/MAC, DHCP, DNS, VPN, NAT)
- Excellence in subnets(including VLSM), setting up dynamic routing(RIPv2, OSPF, BGP, EIGRP)
- Proficient with SSH, Telnet, Account Privileges, VOIP, Cisco Call Manager, SIP

Database Skills:

- Strong command in SQL queries, PL/SQL procedure, functions, triggers, exceptions and transactions
- Flexible to work in different SQL environments (including MySQL, Oracle DB 11g/12c, Oracle SQL Developer, Microsoft SQL Server, and other DB tools)
- Capable of creating new Database from scratch (using Normalization, Integration, User Views, and ERDs), backing up and recovering a database, and granting/provoking DB user access

Other Skills:

- Flexible with different OS (Windows Ultimate Editions, Ubuntu, Kali, Fedora, OS X, and Android) and different server environments (Windows server 2008/2012 R2, Red Hat, Debian, IBM WAS)
- Proficient with Microsoft products including SharePoint, SharePoint Designer, InfoPath, Access, Excel, Word, Outlook and windows server products (Hyper-V, AD, IIS, File Services, and RDP)
- Holds good knowledge of Black Box/White Box, and Jira. Hands on practice with ALM (HP QC)
- Possess skills to monitor/maintain well, write documentations, and create UML/workflow diagrams
- Knowledgeable about Big Data, Data analytics and Data mining

Interpersonal Skills:

- Highly motivated individual with excellent coordinating skills to work in a team as well as individual
- Holds the skills of public speaking, active listening, multitasking, and conflict/crisis management
- Good oral and written communication skills, excellent command of the English language
- Flexible to try new things/ways to improve tasks, ensures the quality of service/product

Continued 1

Arshdeep Dhanjal

30 Willow park Drive Brampton, ON, L6R2N2 Contact No: 647-534-9911 Email: arshdeepdhanjal097@gmail.com

Education:

• Sheridan College – Davis Campus, Brampton ON Computer Systems Technology – Computer Programmer Graduated with honors, GPA: 3.8/4.0

(2015 - 2017)

• Swami Sant Dass Public School - Jalandhar, India Non-Medical (High School Diploma)

(2013 - 2015)

Work Experience:

• Web Analyst/Tester Co-op *Toronto, ON*

(Sept 2017 – Dec 2017)

- Provision sites on Televox network using client requirements and Co-ordinated on several QA tasks with PM's/ Application development teams different QA projects
- o Implemented Content Migration from original sites to new sites along with 301 redirects for webpages
- o Performed documentation for the projects and initiated estimation process by engaging the required people and updating the project estimation sheets
- o Maintain record of daily tasks on spreadsheets through Google Drive to enhance time and efficiency
 - Web Developer / Designer / Tutor Freelance Development, Greater Toronto Area, ON

(Jan 2016 - Present)

- O Developing web applications with complete UI, UX, graphics and image design
- o Working as a developer for a client's website using Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript
- Determining appropriate architecture, and other technical solutions, and make relevant recommendations to clients
- o Learning, understanding and implementing various programming & web based technologies
- O Developing programs and code snippets for providing tutoring sessions to people

Volunteer Work:

• Peer Tutor: (Dec 2013)

Worked as a peer mentor at The Science Hub event in high-School. Duties performed included the following:

- o Teaching students various science experiments and setting up experiment environments
- o Gave several lectures on the topic of "Different Approaches to Learning"
- Office Assistant: (June 2014)

Worked as office assistant for 3 weeks at high-school. Day to day activities involved:

- o Answering general queries phone calls. Helped in troubleshooting the printing problems
- o Provided help in managing the staff data using MS-Excel

Interests and Activities:

- Readings: Journals, Memoirs, Novels, Sci-Fi books
- Fond of cooking and eating
- Fan of all sports. Former Cricket captain for my city
- Learning new and old technologies (Face Detector API, REST API)

References:

Available upon request